<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The speech of Sir Dudly Carlton Lord Ambassadour for the King of Great Britaine made in the Assembly of the Lords the Estates Generall of the vnited Prouinces of the Low Countries. Being assembled at the Haghe. Touching the discord and troubles of the Church and policie, caused by the schismaticall doctrine of Arminius. Exhibited the 6. of October. 1617. Set forth by authoritie.</title>
            <title>Oratie ghedaen door. English</title>
            <author>Carleton, Dudley, Viscount Dorchester, 1573-1632.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1618</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 14 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A17969</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 4629</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S107553</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99843252</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99843252</idno>
            <idno type="VID">7968</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A17969)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 7968)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1060:17)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The speech of Sir Dudly Carlton Lord Ambassadour for the King of Great Britaine made in the Assembly of the Lords the Estates Generall of the vnited Prouinces of the Low Countries. Being assembled at the Haghe. Touching the discord and troubles of the Church and policie, caused by the schismaticall doctrine of Arminius. Exhibited the 6. of October. 1617. Set forth by authoritie.</title>
                  <title>Oratie ghedaen door. English</title>
                  <author>Carleton, Dudley, Viscount Dorchester, 1573-1632.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 9, [3] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by William Iones, for Nathaniel Browne, and are to be sold at the great north doore of Saint Paules Church,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1618.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>A translation of: Oratie ghedaen door.</note>
                  <note>The first leaf and the last leaf are blank.</note>
                  <note>Reproductions of the originals in the Yale University Library ("Early English books, 1475-1640", reel 1060), and the British Library ("Early English newspapers", unit 24, reel 1153).</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Arminianism --  Controversial literature --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-07</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:7968:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:7968:1"/>
            <p>THE SPEECH OF SIR DVDLY CARLTON LORD AMBASSADOVR FOR THE KING OF GREAT BRITAINE, <hi>MADE IN THE ASSEMBLY</hi> of the Lords the Eſtates Generall of the vnited Prouinces of the Low Countries.</p>
            <p>Being aſſembled at the HAGHE.</p>
            <p>TOVCHING THE DISCORD AND TROVBLES OF THE Church and POLICIE, cauſed by the Schiſmaticall Doctrine of ARMINIVS.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Exhibited the 6. of October. 1617.</hi> Set forth by Authoritie.</p>
            <p>LONDON, Printed by <hi>William Iones,</hi> for <hi>Nathaniel Browne,</hi> and are to be ſold at the great North doore of Saint <hi>Paules</hi> Church. 1618.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="speech">
            <pb facs="tcp:7968:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:7968:2"/>
            <head>THE SPEECH OF SIR DVDLY CARLTON LORD EMBASSADOVR FOR the King of Great BRITAINE; made in the <hi>Aſſembly of the Lords the Eſtates Generall</hi> of the vnited Prouinces of the <hi>Low Countries:</hi> Being aſſembled at the <hi>Haghe.</hi> TOVCHING THE DISCORD <hi>AND TROVBLES OF THE CHVRCH</hi> and policy, cauſed by the Schiſmaticall Doctrine of ARMINIVS.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>MY LORDS,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg> HAVE here preſented my ſelfe in your Aſſembly to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge my ſelfe touching the dutie I beare towards God, towards the <hi>King</hi> my Maſter, and towards your Lordſhips. The apprehenſion of the publike calamitie which al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>waies
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:7968:3"/>accompanieth <hi>Schiſme</hi> within the Church, and <hi>Faction</hi> in the State doe giue mee too much ſubiect and cauſe for it. And there being no more cauſe to diſſemble, how that in the ſpace of few yeeres, men haue approached by degrees to the one, &amp; doe at this preſent proceede with full pace to the other of theſe precipices. It were to for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>get the charge which I haue on the one part of his Maieſtie in the qualitie of his Ambaſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dour, and the Oath which I haue made to your Lordſhips as Counſellor of this eſtate, and the coniunct Intereſt of the one with the other, if I ſhould not contribute all that which depends of mee, to ſearch and know exactly the origi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nall, progreſſe and preſent ſtate of this euill, to the end we may be able to apply therevnto the <hi>Remedy</hi> which is moſt neceſſarie.</p>
            <p>It is the Rule of <hi>Hippocrates Deſperatis non adhibere Medicinam.</hi> But (God bee thanked for it,) wee are not as yet come to ſo bad eſtate, although (to ſpeake freely that vvhich is true of this matter) wee are ſo neare to it, ſeeing how the miſchiefe goes forward, growing euery day worſe and worſe, that the <hi>Remedy</hi> will bee fruit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſſe if it be delayed any longer.</p>
            <p>Now for to ſeeke the Originall of this euill any further backe then the time of <hi>Arminius</hi> Profeſſor at <hi>Leyden,</hi> were to diſguiſe the fact. Some others before him it may be haue had the ſame ſcruples, and the ſame troubles in their con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſciences vpon thoſe high points of Predeſtina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:7968:3"/>and the Dependences of it; But the Church hath ſtill continued in her peace and quiet; in ſuch ſort that the fountaine and ſpring of the al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teration which ſince his time ſome haue endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uoured to introduce into the true and ancient Doctrine vvhich you haue alwayes profeſſed, and is receiued and authorized by the common conſent of all the reformed Churches (howſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>euer ſome particular men haue had an opinion a part touching the ſaid points) ought to bee attributed to <hi>Arminius</hi> and to none other.</p>
            <p>Out of the Aſhes and Cinders of <hi>Arminius</hi> are ſprung certaine others, vvho hauing wed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded his particular opinions during his life, haue gone about to introduce them by cunning force into the publike Churches after his death. And not able to effectuate their purpoſe by the ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>narie wayes of <hi>Claſſes,</hi> and <hi>Synodall</hi> Congregati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons they directed themſelues to my Lords the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtates of the Prouince.</p>
            <p>After that, followed the change of the name of an <hi>Arminian</hi> into a <hi>Remonſtrant;</hi> his oppoſite, (vvhich ſeekes to maintaine the Doctrine in the ancient puritie) baptiſed himſelfe with the name of <hi>Contre-Remonſtrant:</hi> But by many inſtances, Counter-inſtances, Propoſitions, Anſweres, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plyes, Diligences and craftie ſubtilties the ſaid <hi>Remonſtrant</hi> at laſt obtaines his cauſe againſt the poore <hi>Contre-Remonſtrant;</hi> gets (in his fauour) a Reſolution of my Lords the Eſtates of <hi>Holland,</hi>
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:7968:4"/>by the pluralitie of voices, though againſt the liking and aduice of many good &amp; great Townes. Triumpheth ouer him <hi>in Concionibus,</hi> and vnder coulour of fiue points (which haue not as yet paſſed a lawfull examination) inſinuates many others among the people; ſtames Inuectiues a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Reformed Religion, and the moſt fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous and reuerend Teachers of it; In many pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces changeth the <hi>Paſtors</hi> and Ancients to ſet into their roomes ſuch others as might be at his deuo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; proceedes with ſuch rigour as well in the Townes as in the Countrie as hee giues occaſion to reuiue in theſe Prouinces, on one ſide the hate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>full name of the <hi>Inquiſition,</hi> and of the other ſide the deplorable words of Churches vvay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling and lamenting; of Churches perſecuted; couering himſelfe alwayes with the title of the Authoritie publike as the onely man that per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed obedience to the Magiſtrate. And gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing the <hi>Contre-Remonſtrant</hi> (vvho begins to looſe his patience, and to ſeparate himſelfe from the body, in Conſequence of this vnhappie ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paration of ſoules) the reproch of <hi>Schiſmatique</hi> and one mutinous and tumultuarie. <hi>Hine Spargere voces in vulgum ambiguas</hi> what was meant to the Magiſtrate. <hi>Et quaerere Conſcius Arma</hi> for his de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence. Men Armed themſelues in the particular Towns &amp; the example paſſeth into the Prouinces.</p>
            <p>Thus you haue in few words the beginning and progreſſe of our euill. The preſent eſtate of it
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:7968:4"/>is an actuall Separation (if not a <hi>Schiſme</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the Church; Iealouſie (not to call it faction) in the eſtate; Animoſities and alterations be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tweene the Magiſtrates, ſowerneſſe and hatred a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt the people: Contempt of the Ordinan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces of the Soueraigne Courts of Iuſtice. Confu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion among the ſouldiers, being bound by diuers Oathes: rumor and tumult betweene the people and the ſouldiers newly leuied and ill diſcipli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, which is come already euen to the ſhedding of innocent bloud, and of that, there hath fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed feare terrour and a generall amazement. All this within the Countrey. From abroad all we vnderſtand of it are the mockeries and ſcoffes of our Enemies, and the diſpleaſure and extreame ſorrow of our Friends.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Contraria inter ſe poſita magis eluceſcunt,</hi> wee ſee then, before the time of <hi>Arminius</hi> what was the eſtate of theſe Prouinces: vnion in the Church and Eſtate; good correſpondence be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tweene the Magiſtrates; Chriſtian loue and cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritie among the people; the Soueraigne Courts of Iuſtice reſpected; the ſouldiers (the ſeruants of your Lordſhips) in peace with all the world except your Enemies; all cheerefulneſſe, all re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ioycing, all acknowledgement of the bleſſing of GOD, which hath appeared miraculouſly in the defence of his cauſe, in the ſight and notice of all the world in your proſperitie; whereat the Enemies of this eſtate, haue remained diſmayed
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:7968:5"/>and amazed, and the friends of it greatly com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forted.</p>
            <p>For the preſent now that euery one ſees ſo cleerely <hi>quantum dimiſſ a petitis praeſtant,</hi> let the <hi>Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monſtrant</hi> take in good part the <hi>Remonſtrance</hi> that followeth, and let him (if he pleaſe) ſerue himſelfe thereof, <hi>Mature redeat repetatque relicta.</hi> But if the Doctrine of <hi>Arminius</hi> be ſo farre ſpread and mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiplyed as there be no more time to giue back, but that it behooueth to paſſe further to a deciſion, which of the two opinions is more conforme and agreeing to the truth of the Word of God; or at the leaſt what ſort of Chriſtian toleration may be permitted without ſcandall in the Church, who ſhall be a competent Iudge in this matter?</p>
            <p>To carry this authoritie to the temporall Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrate, giuing to <hi>Caeſar</hi> that which belongs to <hi>Caeſar,</hi> were to leane and incline too much of that ſide, and to take from <hi>God</hi> that which is <hi>Gods.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Wherefore to proceede with due regard as well towards them to whom <hi>God</hi> hath giuen authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie ouer our bodies, as of thoſe that haue the cure and charge of our ſoules, that which in ſuch oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>currences is alwayes practiſed, and wherevnto within Chriſtendome at all times men haue had recourſe. It is a Nationall <hi>Synode;</hi> I ſay Nationall, becauſe the euill being paſſed from Prouince to Prouince, a <hi>Prouinciall Synode</hi> is not ſufficient, but onely for ſo much as it ſerueth for a prepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ratiue to the Nationall <hi>Synode.</hi> This is the <hi>Remedy</hi>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:7968:5"/>which is found good by the greateſt part of the Prouinces, and that which is recommended to you by the <hi>King</hi> my Maſter.</p>
            <p>As for the Prouinces, I will not play the buſie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>body <hi>in aliena Republica,</hi> therin to Iudge how much euery Prouince in particular ought in ſuch occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons to yeeld to the publike. But whileſt in this bu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſines men ſtand to diſpute the right of Soueraign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie of euery Prouince apart, let them not forget the Oath by which they are conſolidated and clo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed vp into one body which is the <hi>Vnion</hi> of <hi>V<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trecht</hi> grounded vpon Religion. And although they ſeeke to euade and eſcape by ſhew of one Article which is, That euery Prouince hath its power a part in matter of Religion, This ought to bee vnderſtood ſoundly for the maintenance of the pure &amp; ſincere Religion, and not for the autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſation and allowance of new and ſtrange opini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons; And principally in this Prouince where wee are at this preſent, in the contemplation whereof it is to be preſumed that Article was inſerted for the better vpholding of the Reformed Religion in his puritie without being expoſed to the will and pleaſure of the other Prouinces which at that time were not reduced to ſuch an <hi>Vnion</hi> of the Church as they enioy at this preſent.</p>
            <p>But as the points of honour and Soueraigntie are nice and delicate if that reſpect hindreth the conſent of the Prouinces there is no place on the behalfe of his Maieſtie, who giueth you the ſame
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:7968:6"/>counſell as the moſt ſound and wholeſome, <hi>Where there is no pretenſion, there is no preiudice.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>His Maieſtie foreſaw and foretold (ſome yeeres paſt) by his Letters and Miniſters vpon the occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of <hi>Vorſtius</hi> the euils which trouble you at this time; and by other Letters he repreſented to you the little fruit which would ſpring of it in ſuffering the choiſe points of <hi>Predeſtination</hi> to be caried into the chaire and Pulpits, which were too high and to darke for the capacitie of the common people. In the one and the other occaſion his Maieſtie hath witneſſed the ſincerity of his affection giuing his warnings for the zeale he carrieth to the glory of God, and to the dutie of the common Alliance which hath for the foote and foundation the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon ſafety ſettled eſpecially vpon the <hi>Vnity</hi> of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion. And although his wholeſome aduiſes and prayers were not receiued with that reſpect which was due to his good intentions, but rather were entertained with moſt ſiniſter interpretations, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing beene drawne into ſuch ſence and conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quence as was cleane contrarie to his will, his Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſtie notwithſtanding was pleaſed for the third and laſt time (hauing then already begun his voy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>age towards Scotland) to ſollicite you againe in that matter by a Letter of the 20. of <hi>March,</hi> That you would at laſt ſpeedily heale the euill by the way of a <hi>Synode</hi> ſeeing you knew not how to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uent it by other remedies.</p>
            <p>Loe now his Maieſtie (God be thanked for it)
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:7968:6"/>is happily returned from his voyage; wherein (al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though the ſame hath beene long, hauing laſted the ſpace of ſixe monethes) hee hath not changed <hi>Coelum nec animum:</hi> during his abſence I haue for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>borne to ſollicite the anſwere of the ſaid Letter, that I might not render my ſelfe importunate to your Lordſhips out of time and place. But the euill being growen to that dangerous eſtate as I haue vnfolded it; and hauing lately receiued a new charge to the ſame effect, and beholding at this preſent a full Aſſembly of worthy and wiſe perſonages buſied (if I deceiue not my ſelfe) a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout the matter of Religion, I know not how any longer to excuſe my ſelfe, without praying you (My Lords) as I doe with all earneſtnes) to make ſuch Anſwere to the ſaid Letter as may giue teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monie both of the reſpect your Lordſhips beare to the counſels of his Maieſtie, and of the care you haue to the vnion of your Church &amp; Eſtate.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Exhibited in the Aſſembly of the Lords the Eſtates generall of the vnited Prouinces of the Low-Countries, <date>the 6. day of October 1617. <hi>Stilo nouo.</hi>
                  </date> 
               </dateline>
               <signed>And Signed <hi>DVDLY CARLTON.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
